Guide to the Phyllis Moen papers,1978-2004.
Moen, Phyllis papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Phyllis Moen papers, 1978-2004.
23-13-3650
Phyllis Moen
1 cubic ft.
Printed Materials, Research Materials, Publications, Correspondence
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes course material, publications, correspondence, grant proposals, and videos pertaining to Moen's carrer in the Dept. of Human Development and as founding Director of the Bronfenbrenner Life Course Center in the College of Human Ecology.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor Emerita of Human Development and former Director of the Bronfenbrenner Life Course Center, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes course material, publications, correspondence, grant proposals, and videos pertaining to Moen's carrer in the Dept. of Human Development and as founding Director of the Bronfenbrenner Life Course Center in the College of Human Ecology.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Moen, Phyllis; Moen, Phyllis; Bronfrenbrenner Life Course Center.; Cornell University--Faculty; New York State College of Human Ecology. |b Dept. of Human Development.
Subjects:
Home economics--Study and teaching.; New York State College of Human Ecology.--Dept. of Human Development.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
General
Cornell Careers Institute
Videos
SERIES LIST
Series I. General
Series II. Cornell Careers Institute
Series III. Videos
CONTAINER LIST
- General
- Biographical Information (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Course Material: HDFS 354 - "The Family in Cross-Cultural Perspective", 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Course Material- HDFS 650: "The Family in Cross-Cultural Perspective", 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Course Material, 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Course Material, 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Course Material, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Course Material, 1998,1999,2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Articles by Moen, 1985-1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Articles by Moen, 1997-2001 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Articles by Moen and Others, 1989-1999 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Articles by Moen and Others, 2000-2004 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Grant Material Proposal -"Life Transitions and Employment Changes of Mature Women", 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Grant Material - "Family Aspects of Women's Part Time Employment", 1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Grant Material - "The Menopause Transition in Poor Rural Women", 1993 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Grant Material Proposal -"Pathways to Life Quality: A Longitudinal Study of Residential Charge and Adjustment in the Later Years", 1996 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Cornell Careers Institute
- Program: Cornell Retirees Volunteering in Service (CRVIS), 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence - Grant Possibilities - Jim Spencer Letter, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- A Life Course Approach to Working Families: A Research and Training Agenda - Proposal to Sloan Foundation, May 1996 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Cornell Careers Institute Brochures (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Sloan Foundation And Human Ecology Agreement about Budget, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Research Foci for Individuals Using The Couples and Careers Data, September 2000 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Cornell Careers Institute -Interim Report and Sloan Update Report, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Cornell Careers Institute -Goals Report and Cornell Couples and Careers Study Progress Report, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Sloan Foundation Concerns, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Sloan Workshop on Work and Family, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Reviews on Sloan Application, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Cornell Couples and Careers Study - Sample Letters, Letters sent to the Couples who participated, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Its About Time: Couples, Career Strains, Strategies and Successes - Book Proposal and Review, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Photographs -Contact Sheets -Cornell Careers Institute Colloquium Speakers, 1999,2000 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Cornell Employment and Family Careers Institute, 1996-2004 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Cornell University Press - Marketing, 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Eastern Sociological Society Executive Committee, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- "Rethinking Work, Family, and the Life Course" Symposium, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Videos
- To The Contrary Show: Working Innovations Featuring Phyllis Moen, Video1 (Box 1)
- 60 Minutes -"The Age Wave", January 2003; Video2 (Box 1)